

Btech, with an overall experience of 6.5 years and 2+ years experience in Salesforce Admin and Development, with sound hands-on knowledge on APEX, VisualForce, SOQL, SOSL, DML, LWC, PB, WFR, Approval Process in both Classic and Lightning environment



Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: HTC Global Services Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Triggers, Visualforce, Apex, Data Loader, Dml, Functional, Salesforce, Salesforce.com, SFDC, Sales Force

Development, Salesforce CRM, Approvals, Integration, SOAP, WSDL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 14-Dec-20 Last Modified: 14-Dec-20

### Summary

Product Specialist currently working for the United States in Insurance business unit Specialized in Vantage systems, AML systems etc.

Having 4 yrs of experience in Analysis, Development and maintenance of mainframe systems

Good experience in technologies like COBOL, JCL, DB2, VSAM, REXX,CICS

Good experience in Vantage Systems and annuity products like WMA CV15 & CAPSIL

Played significant role in various phases of project life cycle such as Business requirements, analysis, coding, unit testing and Implementation

Answering to business as well as proposing technical queries and implementing fixes for application problems as and when required.

# Work Experience

HTC Global Services as Senior Software Engineer Feb 2019 to Till Date

As part of my project I am engaged with full participation in various phases of SDLC like Analysis, Design, Coding, Testing and Deployment. Also having relevant knowledge in SFDC features like Workflow Rules and Approval Processes, Sharing Rules, Automation Implementation with Process Builder, Workflow Implementation with Objects, Custom Apps, Layout, tabs, Validation Rules along with hands on experience in developing Triggers, Apex Classes and VisualForce Pages.

**DXC Technology** as Professional 1 Product Developer Sep 2018 to Feb 2019

As part of my profile i was engaged with the various phases of project life cycle such as Business requirements, analysis, coding, unit testing and Implementation. Exposure to handle operational changes and functional enhancement requests and implementing fixes for application problems as and when required. Along with this i have also contributed in developing complex IO modules, documented and executed various test plan and test cases based on customer requirements and commercial specification. Worked directly with cross sectional teams to provide solutions to issues as and when required. Contributed also in approaching design solution to clients.

#### Cognizant Technology Solutions as Product Specialist May 2014 to Aug 2018

As part of my project I have been involved in various phases of SDLC including Analysis, Design Coding and Unit Testing. Alongwith handling client calls and providing solutions to business requirement.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from west bengal university of technology in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Certification on Core Java

Certification on Advanced Java

CCP Certification on COBOL, JCL, DB2

Certificate on Salesforce

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Use	d Experience
Windows 98/XP/7, MVS		
Mainframes, Java		
COBOL, JCL, REXX		
Java (Core + advanced basics)		
J2EE, JDBC, JSP, Servlets C, C++		
DB2, MYSQL		
HTML, CSS, JQUERY		
SALESFORCE	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
APEX	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
TRIGGERS	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			
Bengali	Expert			

### **Projects**

Project Title: MIPS reduction

Client: Meijer

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Apr 2019 - May 2019 Project Location: Hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 15

Skill Used: JCL COBOL CICS DB2

Role Description: As part of Module leader I was responsible in understanding the existing application and understanding the changes to be made in the right modul. Provide solution to clients and handling the various changes that need to be done in

the module.

Role: Programmer

Project Details: As part of MIPS reduction project, jobs for transactions are identified which cosume more CPU utilisation thus leading to more cashing out from Client. The objective of this project was to reduce CPU consumption for identified transactions that lead to more usage of time and space for Application servers.

Project Title: DCA Edits BHF wmA Client: Bright House Financial Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Hyderabad

Duration: Nov 2018 - Dec 2018

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 2

Skill Used: Mainframes, Cobol, Db2, Application Development, MFED-Cobol, Github, Squirrel

Role Description: Was responsible for adding/ modifying existing modules to ensure proper functioning of code. Thus

supporting the DCA hard edits on Cost Averaging page on wmA online screen.

Project Details: The Cost Averaging transaction Screen will be modified to edit for additional warning messages and /or hard

edits.

The changes on the screen will be made for the conditions when A) EDCA funds cannot be selected for Allocation change, or B) When EDCA will be temrinated on a contract and remaining funds exist in the "From" fund source C) When attempting to add or update DCA on a contract based on some conditions.

Project Title: Primerica Interface Mods

Client: Bright House Financial Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Nov 2018 - Feb 2019 Project Location: Hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 3

Role: Programmer Skill Used: Mainframes, Cobol, JCL, Db2, Github, MFED-Cobol, Squirrel

Role Description: Responsible for analysis and developing codes to generate Primerica reports on BHF wmA platform. Along with providing solution design to clients to ensure proper functioning of code to generate reports of Primerica. Project Details: Primerica reports as created on legacy mainframe system needs to be run on wmA system in BHF environment. Modernization and migration of existing applications on legacy systems to wmA platform is the core requirement of this project. This required adding/ updating of jobs and job functionality and module and running on BHF system following BHF standards to replicate the exact functionality of Primerica as run on legacy Mainframe systems.

Project Title: Annuity Host fields migration in BHF wmA

Client: Bright House Financial Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2018 - Till Date Project Location: Hyderabad Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Programmer Team Size: 2

Skill Used: Mainframes, Cobol, Db2, MFED-Cobol, Squirrel

Project Details: Annuity Host fields are identified with a Memo\_code of BR and the same are active on wmA v10 on SmartApp. With the latest conversion to wmA v17, SmartApp will be replaced by wmA online. Annuity Host fields need to be converted to wmA v17 environment having the same functionality. Module enhancement is required to support the proper functioning of Annuity Host fields in wmA.

Project Title: Vantage - Capsil Fund Expansion

Client: Metlife

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Feb 2018 - Apr 2018 Project Location: Kolkata Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Module Leader Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Cobol, Db2, VSAM, JCL, Changeman, Fault Analyzer, SDSF, File Manager, Test Preparation, Application

Deployment

Project Details: The objective of this project is to perform the necessary system changes to accommodate Fund Expansion. Fund portfolios are added, merged or removed from the system. Old fund portfolio names are changed to new fund portfolios. This require the various funds to be transferred or allocated to their new fund portfolios. Online (CICS) screen is also changed to accommodate the changes.

Closed/ removed funds will no more be shown on the CTA screen and newly added funds will be displayed. Validation of the new funds will be performed to check whether the funds transferred to the new portfolios exist. This is a purely online screen design requirement using CICS

Project Title: Vantage - CV15 Fund Expansion

Client: Metlife

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Apr 2018 Project Location: Kolkata Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Module Leader Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Cobol, Db2, VSAM, JCL, Changeman, Fault Analyzer, SDSF, File Manager, Test Preparation, Application

Deployment

Project Details: The objective of this project is to perform the necessary system changes to accommodate Fund Expansion. Fund portfolios are added, merged or removed from the system. Old fund portfolio names are changed to new fund portfolios. This require the various funds to be transferred or allocated to their new fund portfolios.

Project Title: Vantage - CV15 DOL Agent Reassignment for inactive agents

Client: Metlife

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Mar 2018 Project Location: Kolkata Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Cobol, Db2, VSAM, JCL, Changeman, Fault Analyzer, SDSF, File Manager, Test Preparation, Application

Deployment

Project Details: The primary objective of this project is to perform Mass agent changes on all orphaned business belonging to MetLife or Brighthouse account so that business can easily identify all these policies and send them any required

correspondences.

Project Title: Vantage - CV15 EM transaction processing

Client: Metlife Insurance

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Nov 2017 - Jan 2018 Project Location: Kolkata Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Cobol, Db2, VSAM, JCL, Changeman, Fault Analyzer, SDSF, File Manager, Test Preparation, Application

Deployment

Project Details: The primary objective of this project was to allow EM transaction processing for all inactive policies for CV15 application. This required modifying existing COBOL modules and JCL changes in order to process EM transactions and print correspondences for the inactive policies as well.

Project Title: AML Application - Retail Separation

Client: Metlife Insurance

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2017 - Nov 2017 Project Location: Kolkata Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Cobol, Db2, VSAM, JCL, Changeman, Fault Analyzer, SDSF, File Manager, Test Preparation, Application

Deployment

Project Details: The objective of this project is to generate separate set of Aggregate and Exception files for policies belonging to separate companies and also decommissioning the filtering criteria. Application changes were made that was necessary to generate separate files for separate companies.

This included writing and modifying new and existing COBOL modules.

Project Title: CDH - Module development

Client: Express Scripts

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Feb 2015 - Sep 2016

Project Location: Kolkata Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Test Engineer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Cobol, Db2, VSAM, JCL, Endevor, Fault Analyzer, SDSF, FileAid, Test Preparation, Application Deployment Project Details: The primary objective of this project was to decrease the time complexity of Inbound Processing for all Divisions and Vendors. The restructuring of the complete process was made that included duplicate checking, processing of the files and generation of reports into two different jobs based on certain conditions.

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Countries: India

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time